Guide to the American School Kikungshan and American School Kikungshan Association Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
American School Kikungshan and American School Kikungshan Association Records
1900-2014
RG 164
Yale University Divinity School Library
10
(23 boxes)
Reports, correspondence, photographs, and collected material document the history of the American School Kikungshan and its graduates. The American School Kikungshan was a school for missionary children established by the Lutheran missions in China. The American School Kikungshan Association is the alumni/ae association of the school.
American School of Kikungshan
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the American School Kikungshan Association.
Biographical / Historical
1914 ASK established on Kikungshan with Agnes Kittlesby as first principal. Predecessors included small schools set up by Hauge Synod and American Lutheran Mission
1927 School moved to Hankow, then evacuated to Shanghai and closed
1928 Fall Reopened in Eric Sovik home in Shekow
1929 Spring Returned to Kikungshan
1930 Oct Fled to Lutheran Missions Home and Agency in Hankow
1931 Jan Returned to Kikungshan
1931 Feb Fled to Lutheran Missions Home and Agency in Hankow
1931 Fall At Redcroft School in Kuling
1934 Fall Reopened at Kikungshan
1938 Jan Evacuated to Cheung Chau, Hong Kong
1941 Jan Evacuated to U.S.; finished school year at Luther Academy in Wahoo, Nebraska
1946 Reopened at Sinyang
1947Dec Evacuated to Lutheran Missions Home and Agency in Hankow
1948 Mar Evacuated to Hong Kong; opened in Ebenezer Home for Blind Girls in Pokfulam
1950Fall Tutorship school opened in rented house in Tao Fong Shan, Hong Kong
1951 Spring Last high school graduation
1952-53 Lillian Landahl tutored half-time, then left on furlough. No replacement found.
1953-55 Six missionary mothers taught classes in their homes.
1955 Home board authorized purchase of station wagon to transport missionary children to Kowloon schools.
1992-2005 The American School Kikungshan Association, an alumni/ae association, was incorporated in 1992. It was officially dissolved in 2005 as many of the graduates were no longer able to attend reunions. Since that time some ASK graduates have been involved in a new organization, China Venture Services, which seeks to foster the development of meaningful relations between the Christian community in North America and the Chinese community, especially in Henan.
Scope and Contents
These records document the history of a school established in 1915 for the children of Lutheran missionaries in China and the school's alumni/ae association. Because of civil unrest in China, the school was often evacuated from Kikungshan (now Jigongshan), a hill resort situated north of the Yangtze River that was the favored summer resort for the foreign residents of Hankow (now Hankou). These records, along with records held at YDSL of the Shanghai American School and North China American School, provide an excellent picture of the lifelong influence of these schools for missionary children.
Series I includes minutes of the Board of the American School Kikungshan, financial records, and correspondence related to the management of the school.
Series II documents the life of the school through its publications - yearbooks and newsletters, as well as programs from school events and compiled information about the school's history. Of particular interest are a 1946 report by Gertrude Sovik that provides detailed information about the operations of the school and a 1994 report about the childhood experiences and health history of ASK graduates.
Series III includes material by and about the alumni/ae and faculty of ASK, including "The Rooster Crows Again: the Story of the American School Kikungshan" by Charlotte Martinson Gronseth and Gertrude Sovik, which includes a summary of the history of the school and reminiscences of alumni/ae.
Series IV documents the American School Kikungshan Association, an alumni/ae group that has an ongoing newsletter and reunions.
Series V contains Collected Materials that relate to the context of the American School Kikungshan, including Lutheran mission reports and periodicals that provide information about the history of ASK.
Arrangement
I. School Organization and Management, 1926-1959
II. School Life and Publications, 1921-1949
III. Alumni/ae/ Faculty Records, 1900-1996
IV. ASK Association Records, 1980-2014
V. Collected Materials, 1921-2003
Children of missionaries -- China; Missions -- China -- Educational work; American School of Kikungshan
- School Organization and Management, 1926-1959; Series I
  - Constitution, reports, corres. to David W. Vikner; minutes of American School Board, 1926-1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bound volume of minutes of Board and related documents, 1929-1934 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Corres. of Casper Skinsnes, Erik Sovik; minutes of Board; financial statement, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Financial accounts, corres. of Earl Dahlstrom to David W. Vikner, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Financial accounts; Board records, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Financial accounts; documents re. repair of house in Hong Kong, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Financial accounts; corres.; Board minutes, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- School Life and Publications, 1921-1949; Series II
  - School publications
    - ASK Yearbook, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - ASK Yearbook, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - ASK Yearbook, 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - ASK Yearbook, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - ASK newsletters: "The Kikungshan Geyser" (1932; title page only); Untitled (1936); "Cock-A-Doodle-Do" (1937), 1932-1937 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Printed newspapers: "The Cock-A-Doodle" (Cheung Chau, Hong Kong), newspaper originals (oversize), 1938-1939 (Box OVd-4)
    - Printed newspapers: "The Cock-A-Doodle", photocopies (oversize), 1938-1939 (Box OVd-4)
    - ASK newsletters:"American Service Kestrel" (1943, 1945); "Chanticleer" (Hong Kong;1948), 1943-1948 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - ASK newsletters: "Chanticleer" and untitled piece about school life, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Documentation of School Life
    - ASK Commencement Programs, 1926-1949 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
    - Misc. (programs, invitations, notices, map of Kikungshan), 1915-1927 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Misc. (programs, invitations), 1933-1949 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Christmas programs in German, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
  - History and reports about ASK
    - ASK Timeline from 1901-1955; compiled by Francis C. Gamelin, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Lists of faculty, students, graduates, list of ASK family burials in China; compiled by FCG (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - ASK Report by Gertrude D. Sovik: information about the school and its faculty, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - ASK Report: information about health services, school supplies, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - ASK Report: information about the library, physical education program, extracurricular activities, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Articles, newspaper clippings, letters about ASK, including special issue of Honan Glimpses (1925 Jan); material re. ASK in "True HEars for God in China" by Frank T. Woodward, 1916-1948, 1979, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - "The Rooster Crows Again: the Story of American School Kikungshan" by Gertrude Sovik: See Series III, Alumni/ae writings
    - "ASK Childhood Experience and Health" report by Grace Ditmanson Adams, R.N., in consultation with Ellis Benson, M.D.; questionnaire form used for compiling report, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Photographs and Memorabilia
    - Gertrude Sovik's ASK diploma, school photo album, and a newspaper article about her (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - ASK flour sack towel, school hymnal (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Photos in China: ASK teachers Kittlesby, Hollestad, Olson (Box 15, Folder 111)
    - Photos in China, undated, students and families (Box 15, Folder 112)
    - Photos in China, 1900-1920, students and families (Box 15, Folder 113)
    - Photos in China, 1930s, students and families, school property (Box 15, Folder 114)
    - Photos in China, 1940s, students and families (Box 15, Folder 115)
    - Photos in the U.S., mostly in Northfield MN, 1950s (Box 15, Folder 116)
    - ASK memorabilia: school programs, insignia, school songs, a final exam, ASK armband (Box 15, Folder 117)
    - Photos: students of ASK, 1916-1936 (Box 18, Folder 143)
    - Photos: Kikungshan and American School buildings, 1916-1936 (Box 18, Folder 144)
    - Photos: Beloved places on Kikungshan, 1916-1936 (Box 18, Folder 145)
    - Photos: special events of ASK, 1916-1936 (Box 18, Folder 146)
    - Photos: the Kuling years, 1932-1949 (Box 18, Folder 147)
    - Photos: 1st flight to Hong Kong, 1938 Jan (Box 18, Folder 148)
    - Photos: school closed and students left for America, 1947 Jan; post-WWII Sinyang, 1932-1949 (Box 18, Folder 149)
    - Photos: misc., 1932-1949 (Box 18, Folder 150)
    - Photos: 2nd flight to Hong Kong, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 151)
    - Photos: ASK faculty, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 152)
- Alumni/ae and Faculty Records, 1900-1996; Series III
  - Writings/oral histories of alumni/ae
    - "In Those Days" by Elliot C. Aandahl [Added to Library's cataloged collection: One Crowded Hour by Elliot Aandahl; In the Crucible by Palmer Anderson] (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "Harp of my Heart" by Grace Jewel Jensen Buster (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "The Pearl and the Dragon" by Winifred Jacobson (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "In Stride with God" by Paul J. Lindell (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "China Memoir" by Hilda Benson Powicke (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "To Be a Pilgrim" by Frances E. Scherer [Added to Library's cataloged collection: Aunt Edith and Lora by Frances Scherer] (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "Angel in Muddy Trousers" by John H. Schlosser (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Transcript of oral history interview of Gertrude Sovik, Midwest China Oral History Project - 3 volumes (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "Closing of the American School of Kikungshan" by Gertrude Sovik (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - "The Rooster Crows Again: the Story of the American School Kikungshan" by Gertrude Sovik (1985) (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - The Rooster Crows Again: the Story of the American School in Kikungshan by Gertrude Sovik and Charlotte Martinson Gronseth, master copy, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 99)
    - The Rooster Crows Again promotion and correspondence, 1978-1995 (Box 13, Folder 100)
    - The Rooster Crows Again originals (Box 14, Folder 102-104)
    - Letter from Carrie Olson in Evangelists Seier (Box 14, Folder 107)
    - Misc writing of ASK Alumni: "Returning Home" H. Daniel Friberg; "As a Spectator in a Chinese service" Agnes M. Thorson; "Beauty Spots in Kikungshan" John Scholsser. (Box 14, Folder 108)
    - Cora Martinson's autobiography, from the Cora Martinson Collection, 1924 (Box 14, Folder 109)
    - Correspondence between early ASKites, from the Cora Martinson Collection, 1913-1919 (Box 14, Folder 110)
    - Summary of oral histories done by Midwest China Oral History Project (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - ASK Faculty Files
    - Aalbur-Carlberg (Box 19, Folder 153)
    - Dahlstrom-Meyer (Box 19, Folder 154)
    - Nelson-Wieneke (Box 19, Folder 155)
    - Ekstrand, Dorothy: correspondence, "The Story of Dorothy Ekstrand", obituaries/life history, 1979-1996 (Box 19, Folder 156)
    - Ekstrand, Dorothy: package prepared by students before her departure of "steamer" letters, one for each day of the voyage, 1936 (Box 19, Folder 157-158)
    - Ekstrand, Dorothy: Chinese correspondence and photographs (Box 19, Folder 159)
    - Kittelsby, Agnes (Box 19, Folder 160)
    - Sovik, Gertrude: personal school memorabilia, correspondence, 1936-1938 (Box 19, Folder 161)
    - Sovik, Gertrude: memoir of China, autobiography, article "The Closing of ASK" (Box 19, Folder 162)
    - Sovik, Gertrude: ASK trip to China, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 163)
    - Sovik, Gertrude: ASK information sheets, life history, obituary (Box 19, Folder 164)
    - Sovik, Gertrude: newspaper clippings, photographs (Box 19, Folder 165)
  - ASK Student Files
    - Aandahl, Elliot (Box 19, Folder 166)
    - Ady, Carolyn and Robert (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - Alexander, Edith, Mildred and Henry James (Box 19, Folder 168)
    - Anderson, Alice and Carol (Box 19, Folder 169)
    - Anderson, Clara and Ruth (Box 19, Folder 170)
    - Ayers, Thomas William and Virginia (Box 19, Folder 171)
    - Baltzer, Harold (Box 19, Folder 172)
    - Bartel Family (Box 19, Folder 173)
    - Beckman (Box 19, Folder 174)
    - Beckon (Box 19, Folder 175)
    - Behrents (Box 19, Folder 176)
    - Benson (John and Lillie) Family (Box 20, Folder 177)
    - Benson (Nels and Alice) Family (Box 20, Folder 178)
    - Berkin, Birkel, Birrel, Blackstone (Box 20, Folder 179)
    - Bly (Box 20, Folder 180)
    - Borg, Breen, Braaten (Box 20, Folder 181)
    - Brandauer, Bruce (Box 20, Folder 182)
    - Bruhl (Box 20, Folder 183)
    - Campbell, Carter, Carlson (Box 20, Folder 184)
    - Colberg-Cotter (Box 20, Folder 185)
    - Daehlin (Box 20, Folder 186)
    - Distad (Box 20, Folder 187)
    - Ditmanson (Box 20, Folder 188)
    - Dwight (Box 20, Folder 189)
    - Edwins (Box 20, Folder 190)
    - Ekeland-Ekvall (Box 20, Folder 191)
    - Fauske (Box 20, Folder 192)
    - Fedde (Box 20, Folder 193)
    - Fielder (Box 20, Folder 194)
    - Filman, Frank, French (Box 20, Folder 195)
    - Friberg (Box 20, Folder 196)
    - Goforth, Graven, Green (Box 20, Folder 197)
    - Griebenow-Grinnell (Box 20, Folder 198)
    - Hall-Hannerz (Box 20, Folder 199)
    - Hansen (Box 20, Folder 200)
    - Hanson (Box 20, Folder 201)
    - Harris (Box 20, Folder 202)
    - Harrison-Haugan-Herring (Box 20, Folder 203)
    - Holm-Hompland (Box 20, Folder 204)
    - Jacobson (Box 21, Folder 205)
    - Jensen-Johnson (Box 21, Folder 206)
    - King-Konsterlie-Kristensen (Box 21, Folder 207)
    - Landahl (Box 21, Folder 208)
    - Larsen-Lawton (Box 21, Folder 209)
    - Lee (Box 21, Folder 210)
    - Lindbeck (Box 21, Folder 211)
    - Lindell (Box 21, Folder 212)
    - Lindquist-Lundeen (Box 21, Folder 213)
    - Martinson (Box 21, Folder 214)
    - Matson, McClure, Mewshaw (Box 21, Folder 215)
    - Mortensen (Box 21, Folder 216)
    - Nelson (Box 21, Folder 217)
    - Nesse-Netland (Box 21, Folder 218)
    - Nordlund (Box 21, Folder 219)
    - Nowack (Box 21, Folder 220)
    - Olson-Overmeyer (Box 21, Folder 221)
    - Pannabecker (Box 21, Folder 222)
    - Peterson-Raetz (Box 21, Folder 223)
    - Ramsay (Box 21, Folder 224)
    - Rankin-Ray (Box 21, Folder 225)
    - Roberts (Box 21, Folder 226)
    - Ruhl-Savage (Box 21, Folder 227)
    - Schlosser (Box 21, Folder 228)
    - Schwendenner (Box 21, Folder 229)
    - Seaton-Silva (Box 22, Folder 230)
    - Skepstad (Box 22, Folder 231)
    - Skinsnes (Box 22, Folder 232)
    - Smith (Box 22, Folder 233)
    - Sovik: Ansgar, Edgar, Erik (Box 22, Folder 234)
    - Sovik: Arne, Edward, Margaret (Box 22, Folder 235)
    - Stewart, Stotts, Swenson (Box 22, Folder 236)
    - Thiessen-Thomas (Box 22, Folder 237)
    - Thorson (Box 22, Folder 238)
    - Truax (Box 22, Folder 239)
    - Trued (Box 22, Folder 240)
    - Trygstad (Box 22, Folder 241)
    - Tvedt (Box 22, Folder 242)
    - Valder, Van Dyck, Van Etten (Box 22, Folder 243)
    - Vikner (Box 22, Folder 244)
    - Voth (Box 22, Folder 245)
    - Wahl (Box 22, Folder 246)
    - Werdal (Box 22, Folder 247)
    - Whipple-White (Box 22, Folder 248)
    - Wold (Box 22, Folder 249)
    - Woodward (Box 22, Folder 250)
- Records of the ASK Association, 1980-2014; Series IV
  - Organizational records
    - The China-Born organization, ca. 1941 (Box 16, Folder 118)
    - ASK association records: Board of Directors, minutes, agendas, financial reports, 1991-2003 (Box 16, Folder 119)
    - Endowment, established 1998, 1998-2001 (Box 16, Folder 120)
    - ASK correspondence, 1979-2001 (Box 16, Folder 121)
    - ASK database/address lists, 1940-1998 (Box 16, Folder 122)
    - Newhouse Project - China Missions Video: contract, mission, correspondence, 1998-99 (Box 16, Folder 123)
    - Award to David Edwins from the Association for Foreign and Chinese Cultural Friendship, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 124)
    - Memorials/funeral services for former ASKites, 1992-2002 (Box 16, Folder 125)
    - Moongate memorial: correspondence, photos, reports, plans, 1990s (Box 16, Folder 126)
  - Publications
    - ASK Association Newsletter; Chanticleer II newsletter, 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Chanticleer II newsletter, 1997-2000 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Chanticleer II newsletter, 1993-2003 (Box 16, Folder 127)
    - ASK directory, 1980, 1985,1988 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - ASK directory, July 1991 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Reunions
    - ASK reunions and directories, 1958, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - ASK reunion, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Post-reunion correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - ASK reunion, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - ASK reunion: information and programs, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - ASK reunion: thank you letters, newspaper clippings, post-reunion correspondence, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - ASK reunion: planning committee letters/minutes, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - ASK reunion: information, programs, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - ASK reunion: invoices, newspaper articles, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - ASK reunion: post-reunion correspondence, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - ASK reunion: ASK Association articles and by-laws, program committee meeting minutes and correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - ASK reunion: post-reunion correspondence, newspaper articles, report about the reunion, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - ASK reunion: information, programs, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - ASK reunion: post-reunion correspondence, ASK Association financial report, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - 1997 ASK reunion: student/faculty lists; timeline; financial report; misc (Box 17, Folder 128)
    - 1997 ASK reunion: presentations; programs and services (Box 17, Folder 129)
    - 1997 ASK reunion: logistics, registration, retreat center (Box 17, Folder 130)
    - 1997 ASK reunion: correspondence (Box 17, Folder 131)
    - 2000 ASK reunion: student/faculty lists; database information; timeline; archives list (Box 17, Folder 132)
    - 2000 ASK reunion: logistics, registration, retreat center information (Box 17, Folder 134)
    - 2000 ASK reunion: correspondence, misc. (Box 17, Folder 135)
    - 2003 ASK reunion: registration, schedule, logistics, banquet speaker (Box 17, Folder 136)
    - 2003 ASK reunion: service and hymns (Box 17, Folder 137)
    - 2003 ASK reunion: histories, correspondence, Moongate update (Box 17, Folder 138)
  - Reunion and Alumni/ae Photographs
    - Photographs of retired faculty members (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Misc. photographs of former students and their families (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Photographs from the Northfield, Medicine Lake, and other reunions, 1927, 1931, 1936, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - 1980 reunion photographs (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - 1980 reunion photographs (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - 1980 reunion photographs: banquet (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - 1980 reunion photographs: Kittelsby plaque and ceremony (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - 1980 reunion photographs: alumni/ae and their photographs from various trips to modern-day Kikungshan (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - 1980 reunion: group photographs (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - 1985 reunion photographs (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - 1988 reunion: group photographs (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - 1991 reunion: group photographs (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - 1991 reunion photographs (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - 1991 reunion photographs (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - 1994 reunion photographs (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - Misc. photographs of former students and their families (Box 6, Folder 71)
    - 1997 reunion photographs (Box 17, Folder 139)
    - 2003 reunion photographs (Box 17, Folder 140)
    - 1982 ASK tour to China: photos (Box 17, Folder 141)
    - 1982 ASK tour to China: reports and misc. (Box 17, Folder 142)
  - Addendum, 1974-2010
    - ASK Association Certificate of Incorporation, Articles of Incorporation, By-Laws and associated documentation, 1987-1992 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - ASK Association minutes of Annual meeting (2003), Executive Committee (2004); correspondence re. ASK Scholarship Fund, dissolution of organization in 2005, 2003-2004 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence re. ASK Association mini-reunion with report re. work of China Venture Services in Jigonshan (Kikungshan), 2010 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - VHS tape of Dorothy Bruhl Anderson-Galloway at 2003 ASK Reunion (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Writings of ASK graduates: "I Remember" by Magda G. Lindbeck; "Growing Up in China" by Ruth Vikner Gamelin; Booklet for 90th anniversary of Union Lutheran Theological Seminary in Shekow, Hupeh by Waldo Wold, 1974, 2003, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 5-6)
    - Reunion information; obituaries for ASK alumni Arne and Edward Sovik, 2014 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Historical statement: "Roots of ASK", n.d. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Information about China Service Ventures, including DVD "Near to Heaven: Jigongshan and Missionary History", from Charlotte Gronseth (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Collected Material, 1921-2003; Series V
  - Related to Lutheran missions in China
    - "China" - pamphlet re. work of Augustana Synod, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Lutheran United Mission reports, 1921, 1922, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - Lutheran United Mission reports, 1924, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - Lutheran United Mission reports, 1926, 1929, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - Lutheran United Mission reports, 1931, 1932, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 77)
    - Lutheran United Mission reports, 1934, 1935, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - Gleanings Magazine, 1932 Jul, 1937 Jan (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - China Gleanings Magazine, 1937 Apr, Jul (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - China Gleanings, 1937 Oct (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Guide to Kikungshan (2 copies), 1925 (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Kuling American School newsletters, 1933, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - Unidentified photo album (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - Photograph album presented to Sister Christine Johnson by the teachers of I Kwong Girls' School, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - "Sister Christine's Children" - pamphlet arranged by Mrs. Eric Sovik (Box 7, Folder 88)
    - Books re. China: China in Revival, The Changing China Scene by Gustav Carlber, Tjugu Ar Kina by John L. Benson, Giants Walked Among Us: The Story of Paul and Ina Bartel, by Anthony G. Bollback, This Mountain is Mine, by Margaret Epp, and Jigongshanzhi by Henanrenmin Chubanshe (in chinese), [The following book was received with ASK materials but added to Library's cataloged collection in order to provide wider access: Near to Heaven: Western Architecture in China's Old Summer Resorts by Tess Johnston and Deke Erh] (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - Chinese language material: a novel, and "Religious Instruction for Secondary Schools" (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - Copies of Hymns (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - Articles "Old China Hands" author unknown, and "View of Old China", Jerry Hulse (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - 16 audio cassettes: miscellaneous, including related to reunions, memorial service, lectures by ASK alumni/ae (Box 9)
    - Videocassettes: 1988 ASK Reunion at Gustavus, Chas Roberts and 1987 Underground Church - Changsha; Moongate Dedication, 1998; Chinese Video of ASK Moongate Groundbreaking and subsequent banquet with Sinyang Authorities and Tourist Promotion beginning with Jigongshan; 1992 Return to China; The Christian Church in China: A Story of Faith; Service at Kingkushan Church, 1992; Moongate Dedication, 9/21/1998 produced by Jade Tree Trail, 1988-1998 (Box 10, Folder 96)